<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>freebsd on JO Jaeyoung | 조재영</title>
    <link>https://jaese.github.io/tags/freebsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in freebsd on JO Jaeyoung | 조재영</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 03:08:43 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaese.github.io/tags/freebsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running a Service on FreeBSD: the rc.d scripting</title>
      <link>https://jaese.github.io/posts/running-a-service-on-freebsd-rc-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 03:08:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaese.github.io/posts/running-a-service-on-freebsd-rc-d/</guid>
      <description>Coming from Linux, I thought installing and running a service/daemon on FreeBSD was somewhat unintuitive, so I am writing a note.
I had been using FreeBSD 13.0 running on RPi 4 as a router to my home network since I set it up early this year. FreeBSD had been a solid platform. It was interesting and not-too-frustrating to set up the firewall, dhcpd, and DNS server on FreeBSD because they are well integrated with the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home network v1</title>
      <link>https://jaese.github.io/posts/home-network-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 15:15:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaese.github.io/posts/home-network-v1/</guid>
      <description>It was long overdue I learned the basics of IP networking, and there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a better way than to learn it hands-on by setting up my own home network.
Before then, I&amp;rsquo;d been using the same WiFi hub installed by the ISP when I moved in. (By the way, if you are using the WiFi hub installed by D&amp;rsquo;Live, be aware that it exposes the configuration UI on port 8080 to the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeBSD on RPi 4</title>
      <link>https://jaese.github.io/posts/freebsd-on-rpi4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:11:23 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaese.github.io/posts/freebsd-on-rpi4/</guid>
      <description>As of now, the prebuilt SD card image for RPI (3/4) of FreeBSD 13.0 doesn&amp;rsquo;t run out of the box on RPi 4 due to an issue with the bootloader and requires replacing the bootloader binary on the SD card. If you have a Raspberry PI OS installation and want to try FreeBSD on RPi 4, you can follow these steps:
Download and flash FreeBSD-13.0-RELEASE-arm64-aarch64-RPI.img.xz to an SD card.
Build U-Boot from recent checkout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
