<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>raspberrypi on JO Jaeyoung | 조재영</title>
    <link>https://jaese.github.io/tags/raspberrypi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in raspberrypi on JO Jaeyoung | 조재영</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaese.github.io/tags/raspberrypi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a K3S cluster</title>
      <link>https://jaese.github.io/posts/hello-k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaese.github.io/posts/hello-k3s/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to set up a Kubernetes cluster on my networking lab that consists of three RPis and a PC, and run some actual workload. I used K3S, a lightweight Kubernetes distribution, because it seemed to be the one to go to for running Kubernetes on RPis, ex. Jeff Geerling&amp;rsquo;s video on installing K3S. For image registry, I tried Harbor open source registry v2.4.1. The cluster ingress is fronted by a reverse proxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home network v1</title>
      <link>https://jaese.github.io/posts/home-network-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 15:15:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaese.github.io/posts/home-network-v1/</guid>
      <description>It was long overdue I learned the basics of IP networking, and there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a better way than to learn it hands-on by setting up my own home network.
Before then, I&amp;rsquo;d been using the same WiFi hub installed by the ISP when I moved in. (By the way, if you are using the WiFi hub installed by D&amp;rsquo;Live, be aware that it exposes the configuration UI on port 8080 to the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeBSD on RPi 4</title>
      <link>https://jaese.github.io/posts/freebsd-on-rpi4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:11:23 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaese.github.io/posts/freebsd-on-rpi4/</guid>
      <description>As of now, the prebuilt SD card image for RPI (3/4) of FreeBSD 13.0 doesn&amp;rsquo;t run out of the box on RPi 4 due to an issue with the bootloader and requires replacing the bootloader binary on the SD card. If you have a Raspberry PI OS installation and want to try FreeBSD on RPi 4, you can follow these steps:
  Download and flash FreeBSD-13.0-RELEASE-arm64-aarch64-RPI.img.xz to an SD card.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
